<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<footnotes content-type="text/markdown">

   <footnote id="J1"><![CDATA[ In authorizing the use of frequencies below 8.3kHz, it shall be ensured
that no harmful interference is thereby caused to the services to which the bands
above 8.3kHz are allocated.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J2"><![CDATA[ Use of this frequency band by stations in the meteorological aids
service is limited to passive use only. In this frequency band, meteorological aids
stations shall not claim protection from stations of the radionavigation service
submitted for notification to the Bureau prior to 1 January 2013. For sharing
between stations of the meteorological aids service and stations in the
radionavigation service submitted for notification after this date, Recommendation
ITU-R RS.1881 should be applied.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J3"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the maritime mobile service is
limited to class A1A or F1B emissions by the coast stations only. However, the use
of class J2B or J7B emissions may be authorized to coast stations on condition that
those emissions do not exceed the necessary bandwidth normally used for class A1A
or F1B emissions.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J4"><![CDATA[ The stations of services to which this band is allocated may transmit
standard frequency and time signals. Such stations shall be afforded protection from
harmful interference.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J5"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the fixed service is limited to class
A1A, F1B, A2C, A3C, F1C or F3C emissions.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J6"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the maritime mobile service is
limited to class A1A, F1B, A2C, A3C, F1C, F3C, J2B, or J7B emissions.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J7"><![CDATA[ The stations of the amateur service operating in this band shall not
exceed an equivalent isotropic radiated power (e.i.r.p.) of 1W or cause harmful
interference to stations of the radionavigation service operating in the countries
listed on No.5.67 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J8"><![CDATA[ This frequency band in the radionavigation land stations of the maritime
radionavigation service may be used to transmit the differential GPS data and
supplementary navigational information.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J9"><![CDATA[ In order to protect the intermediate frequencies of medium-wave
broadcasting receivers, assignment of frequencies in the band 450-460 kHz is
restricted to cases in which operation in that band does not cause harmful
interference to the reception of standard broadcasting signals.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J10"><![CDATA[ When establishing the radionavigation coast stations in the NAVTEX
service on the frequencies 490 kHz, 518 kHz and 4209.5 kHz, it is necessary to
coordinate the operating characteristics in accordance with the procedures of the
International Maritime Organization (IMO) (see Resolution 339 (Rev.WRC-97)).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J11"><![CDATA[ The maximum equivalent isotropically radiated power (e.i.r.p.) of
stations in the amateur service using frequencies in this frequency band shall not
exceed 1 W. In this frequency band, stations in the amateur service shall not cause
harmful interference to, or claim protection from, stations of the aeronautical
radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J12"><![CDATA[ The frequency 490kHz is to be used exclusively for the transmission by
coast stations of navigational and meteorological warnings and urgent information to
ships, by means of narrow-band direct-printing telegraphy. In using the band
415-495kHz for the aeronautical radionavigation service, it shall be ensured that no
harmful interference is caused to the frequency 490kHz. In using the frequency band
472-479 kHz for the amateur service, it shall ensure that no harmful interference is
caused to the frequency 490 kHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J13"><![CDATA[ The frequency 518kHz is to be used exclusively for transmission by
coast stations in the international NAVTEX service of meteorological and
navigational warnings and urgent information to ships, by means of narrow-band
direct-printing telegraphy.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J14"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by broadcasting services is subject to
conformity with the Regional Agreements (Geneva, 1975), (Notification No.810 of
the Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications, 1976), on the use of the MF band in
Regions 1 and 3 and the LF band in Region 1 by the broadcasting services.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J15"><![CDATA[ This frequency allocated to the broadcasting services or the
broadcasting-satellite services shall be that stipulated in Article 26, Paragraph 2(5) a),
of the Radio Law.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J16"><![CDATA[ The frequencies 2174.5kHz, 4177.5kHz, 6268kHz, 8376.5kHz,
12520kHz and 16695kHz are international distress frequencies for narrow-band 
direct-printing telegraphy.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J17"><![CDATA[ The frequency 2182kHz is an international distress, calling and
response frequency for radiotelephony, and is to be used exclusively for class J3E
emissions. This frequency’s guard band is 2173.5-2190.5kHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J18"><![CDATA[ The carrier frequencies 2182kHz, 3023kHz, 5680kHz, 8364kHz as well
as the frequencies 121.5MHz, 156.525MHz, 156.8MHz, 243MHz, 10003kHz,
14993kHz, and 19993kHz may also be used, in accordance with the procedures for
terrestrial radiocommunication services, for search and rescue operations concerning
manned space vehicles. The bandwidth of any individual transmission shall not
exceed ± 3 kHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J19"><![CDATA[ The frequencies 2187.5kHz, 4207.5kHz, 6312kHz, 8414.5kHz,
12577kHz and 16804.5kHz are international distress frequencies for digital selective
calling.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J20"><![CDATA[ The carrier frequencies 3023kHz and 5680kHz may also be used by
stations of the maritime mobile service engaged in coordinated search and rescue
operations.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J21"><![CDATA[ The band 3155-3195kHz may also be used for low-power wireless
hearing aids.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J22"><![CDATA[ The carrier frequencies 4125kHz and 6215kHz are the frequencies
auxiliary to the carrier frequency 2182kHz. These frequencies are to be international
calling and response frequencies for radiotelephony.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J23"><![CDATA[ The frequency 4209.5kHz is used exclusively for the transmission by
coast stations of meteorological and navigational warnings and urgent information to
ships by means of narrow-band direct-printing techniques.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J24"><![CDATA[ The frequencies 4210kHz, 6314kHz, 8416.5kHz, 12579kHz,
16806.5kHz, 19680.5kHz, 22376kHz and 26100.5kHz are the international
frequencies for the transmission of Maritime Safety Information (MSI).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J25"><![CDATA[ In principle, the A1A radio frequency 4630kHz is used exclusively for
setting up an emergency communication channel, and once the channel is open, the
emergency communication is carried on the radio waves regularly used. However,
this limitation may be eased when emergency communication through regular radio
waves is impossible.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J26"><![CDATA[ Stations in the radiolocation service shall not cause harmful interference
to, or claim protection from, stations operating in the fixed or mobile services.
Applications of the radiolocation service are limited to oceanographic radars
operating in accordance with Resolution 612 (Rev.WRC-12).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J27"><![CDATA[ The use of the bands 5900-5950 kHz, 7300-7350 kHz, 9400-9500 kHz,
11600-11650 kHz, 12050-12100 kHz, 13570-13600 kHz, 13800-13870 kHz,
15600-15800 kHz, 17480-17550 kHz and 18900-19020 kHz by the broadcasting
service is subject to the application of the procedure of Article 12, and is encouraged
to facilitate the introduction of digitally modulated emissions in accordance with the
provisions of Resolution 517 (Rev.WRC-07).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J28"><![CDATA[ This band is allocated to the fixed service on a primary basis and to the
mobile service except aeronautical mobile (R) service on a secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J29"><![CDATA[ The following bands are designated for industrial, scientific and medical
(ISM) applications based on the results of ITU-R research.
6765-6795kHz (center frequency 6780kHz),
61-61.5GHz (center frequency 61.25GHz),
122-123GHz (center frequency 122.5GHz), and
244-246GHz (center frequency 245GHz)
Additional assignment of frequencies in the following bands to stations
of the fixed and land mobile services is suspended for the time being.
6765 - 6795kHz (center frequency 6780kHz)
244 - 246GHz (center frequency 245GHz)
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J30"><![CDATA[ This band may be used by stations in the fixed service and the land
mobile service on condition that harmful interference is not caused to the
broadcasting service. When using frequencies for these services, administrations are
urged to use the minimum power required and to take account of the seasonal use of
frequencies by the broadcasting service published in accordance with the Radio
Regulations.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J31"><![CDATA[ The stations of services to which the band 7995-8005kHz is allocated
may transmit standard frequency and time signals.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J32"><![CDATA[ The carrier frequencies 8291kHz, 12290kHz and 16420kHz are distress
and calling frequencies for radiotelephony.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J33"><![CDATA[ Stations in the radiolocation service shall not cause harmful interference
to, or claim protection from, stations operating in the fixed service. Applications of 
- 60 -
the radiolocation service are limited to oceanographic radars operating in accordance
with Resolution 612 (Rev.WRC-12).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J34"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the amateur service is restricted to
cases in which operation does not cause harmful interference to the foreign radio
stations whose service is except the amateur service operating in accordance with the
Table of Frequency Allocations of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J35"><![CDATA[ This band is used by the fixed service for provision of services related
to aircraft flight safety.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J36"><![CDATA[ In assigning frequencies to stations of other services to which the
following bands are allocated, all practicable steps shall be taken to protect the radio
astronomy service from harmful interference. Emissions from spaceborne or
airborne stations can be particularly serious sources of interference to the radio
astronomy service (see Nos. 4.5 and 4.6, and Article 29 of the RR).
13360-13410kHz, 4990-5000MHz, 92-94GHz,
25550-25670kHz, 6650-6675.2MHz, 94.1-100GHz,
37.5-38.25MHz, 10.6-10.68GHz, 102-109.5GHz,
73-74.6MHz, 14.47-14.5GHz, 111.8-114.25GHz,
322-328.6MHz, 22.01-22.21GHz, 128.33-128.59GHz,
406.1-410MHz, 22.21-22.5GHz, 129.23-129.49GHz,
608-614MHz, 22.81-22.86GHz, 130-134GHz,
1330-1 400MHz, 23.07-23.12GHz, 136-148.5GHz,
1610.6-1 613.8MHz, 31.2-31.3GHz, 151.5-158.5GHz,
1660-1 670MHz, 31.5-31.8GHz, 168.59-168.93GHz,
1718.8-1722.2MHz, 36.43-36.5GHz, 171.11-171.45GHz,
2655-2690MHz, 42.5-43.5GHz, 172.31-172.65GHz,
3260-3267MHz, 42.77-42.87GHz, 173.52-173.85GHz,
3332-3339MHz, 43.07-43.17GHz, 195.75-196.15GHz,
3345.8-3352.5MHz, 43.37-43.47GHz, 209-226GHz,
4825-4835MHz, 48.94-49.04GHz, 241-250GHz,
4950-4990MHz, 76-86GHz, 252-275GHz
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J37"><![CDATA[ The following bands are designated for industrial, scientific and medical
(ISM) applications. Radiocommunication services operating within these bands must
accept harmful interference that may be caused by these applications.
13553-13567kHz (center frequency 13560kHz),
26957-27283kHz (center frequency 27120kHz),
40.66-40.70MHz (center frequency 40.68MHz),
2400-2500MHz (center frequency 2450MHz),
5725-5875MHz (center frequency 5800MHz), and
24-24.25GHz (center frequency 24.125GHz)
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J38"><![CDATA[ The stations of services to which the band 15995-16005kHz is allocated
may transmit standard frequency and time signals.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J39"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band is restricted to cases in which operation
does not cause harmful interference to the foreign radio stations whose service is
except the space research service operating in accordance with the Table of
Frequency Allocations of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J40"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the fixed service shall be only for aircraft flight
safety service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J41"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band is restricted to cases in which operation
does not cause harmful interference to the radio stations whose service is except the
radiolocation service operating in accordance with the Table of Frequency
Allocations of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J42"><![CDATA[ The frequency 75MHz is assigned to marker beacons. Frequencies close
to the limits of the guard band 74.8-75.2MHz shall not be assigned to stations or
other services which, because of their power or geographical position, might cause
harmful interference or otherwise place a constraint on marker beacons.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J43"><![CDATA[ This band is also allocated on a primary basis to the aeronautical mobile
(R) service, limited to systems operating in accordance with recognized international
aeronautical standards. Such use shall be in accordance with Resolution 413
(Rev.WRC-07). The use of the band 108-112 MHz by the aeronautical mobile (R)
service shall be limited to systems composed of ground-based transmitters and
associated receivers that provide navigational information in support of air
navigation functions in accordance with recognized international aeronautical
standards.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J44"><![CDATA[ In this band, the frequency 121.5MHz is the aeronautical emergency
frequency and, where required, the frequency 123.1MHz is the aeronautical 
frequency auxiliary to 121.5MHz. Mobile stations of the maritime mobile service
may communicate on these frequencies for distress and safety purposes or collection
of Satellite Position-Indicating Radiobeacons installed Simplified Voyage Data
Recorder (S-VDR) with stations of the aeronautical mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J45"><![CDATA[ The frequency bands 118-118.875MHz, 121.6-121.975MHz and
124.3-124.375MHz may also be used by stations of the land mobile service that
engage in ground control operations within airports.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J46"><![CDATA[ The band 132-136MHz is also allocated to the aeronautical mobile (OR)
service on a primary basis. In assigning frequencies to stations of the aeronautical
mobile (OR) service, account shall be taken of the frequencies assigned to stations in
the aeronautical mobile (R) service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J47"><![CDATA[ In making assignments to space stations in the mobile-satellite service
in this band, all practicable steps shall be taken to protect the radio astronomy
service in the bands 150.05-153MHz, 322-328.6MHz, 406.1-410MHz and
608-614MHz from harmful interference by unwanted emissions.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J48"><![CDATA[ In the bands:
137-138 MHz,
 400.15-401 MHz,
 1 525-1 610 MHz,
 21.4-22 GHz,
Resolution 739 (WRC-07) applies.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J49"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is limited to
non-geostationary satellite systems.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J50"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is subject to
coordination under No.9.11A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J51"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may also be used in the portable mobile service
and fixed service that is closely related to the land mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J52"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may be used for the transmission of
radiocommunications in commercial mobile services except for the basic
broadcasting stipulated in Article 6, Paragraph 2, of the Radio Law, limited to
stations for broadcasting services.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J53"><![CDATA[ Frequencies in this band may also be allocated for the space operation
service (Earth-to-space) on a primary basis, on condition that the Japanese
administration obtains the agreements of other administrations in accordance with
No.9.21 of the RR. The bandwidth of any individual transmission shall not exceed
± 25 kHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J54"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is subject to
coordination under No.9.11A of the RR. The mobile-satellite service shall not
constrain the development and use of the fixed, mobile and space operation services
in the band 148-149.9MHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J55"><![CDATA[ Stations of the mobile-satellite service in this band shall not cause
harmful interference to, or claim protection from, stations of the fixed or mobile
services operating in the countries listed on No.5.221 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J56"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is subject to
coordination under No.9.11A of the RR. The mobile-satellite service shall not
constrain the development and use of the radionavigation-satellite service in the
bands 149.9-150.05MHz and 399.9-400.05MHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J57"><![CDATA[ The emissions of frequencies in this band by the
radionavigation-satellite service may also be used by receiving earth stations of the
space research service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J58"><![CDATA[ The use of the bands 149.9-150.05MHz and 399.9-400.05MHz by the
mobile-satellite service (Earth-to-space) are limited to the land mobile-satellite
service (Earth-to-space) until 1 January 2015.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J59"><![CDATA[ The allocation of the bands 149.9-150.05MHz and 399.9-400.05MHz to
the radionavigation-satellite service shall be effective until 1 January 2015.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J60"><![CDATA[ The frequency 156.525MHz is to be used exclusively for digital
selective calling for distress, safety and calling.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J61"><![CDATA[ The frequency 156.8MHz is the international distress and calling
frequency for radiotelephony.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J62"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may also be used by the mobile service except for
the maritime mobile service, or the fixed service that are closely related to the 
maritime mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J63"><![CDATA[ The use of the frequency bands 156.7625-156.7875MHz and
156.8125-156.8375MHz by the mobile-satellite service (Earth-to-space) is limited to
the reception of automatic identification system (AIS) emissions of longrange AIS
broadcast messages (Message 27, see Recommendation ITU-R M.1371). With the
exception of AIS emissions, emissions in these frequency bands by systems
operating in the maritime mobile service for communications shall not exceed 1 W.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J64"><![CDATA[ The use of the automatic identification system in the frequency bands
161.9625-161.9875MHz and 162.0125-162.0375MHz by the aeronautical mobile
(OR) service is limited to aircraft stations for the purpose of search and rescue
operations and other safety-related communications.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J65"><![CDATA[ The use of the frequency bands 161.9625-161.9875MHz and
162.0125-162.0375MHz by the mobile-satellite service (Earth-to-space) is limited to
the reception of automatic identification system emissions from stations operating in
the maritime mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J66"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may also be used by the mobile service except for
the land mobile service, which is closely related to the land mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J67"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may also be used by the fixed service that is
closely related to the mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J68"><![CDATA[ A part of the band 806-960 MHz may also be used by International
Mobile Telecommunications (IMT) in accordance with Resolutions 224
(Rev.WRC-07) and 749 (WRC-07).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J69"><![CDATA[ The frequency 243MHz is for use by survival craft stations and
equipment used for survival purposes.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J70"><![CDATA[ The frequency band 247.9-250.2MHz may also be used by stations of
the fixed service for broadcast communication on a primary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J71"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by unlicensed low-power service shall not claim
protection from, and shall not cause harmful interference to, other stations operating
in accordance with this Frequency Allocation Table.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J72"><![CDATA[ Stations of the aeronautical mobile service that currently operate in this
frequency band may continue their operations for the time being.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J73"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may also be used by the mobile service except for
the maritime mobile service that is closely related to the maritime mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J74"><![CDATA[ Emissions of the standard frequency 400.1MHz shall be confined in a
band of ± 25kHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J75"><![CDATA[ This band is also allocated to the space research service in the
space-to-space direction for communications with manned space vehicles. In this
allocation, the space research service will not be regarded as a safety service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J76"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is subject to
coordination under No.9.11A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J77"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the fixed service is limited to the
cases when it is closely related to the meteorological service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J78"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is limited to Satellite
Emergency Position-Indicating Radiobeacons is prohibited.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J79"><![CDATA[ Any emission capable of causing harmful interference to Satellite
Emergency Position-Indicating Radiobeacons.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J80"><![CDATA[ Use of this band by the space research service is limited to
communications within 5 km of an orbiting, manned space vehicle. In this frequency
band the space research service shall not claim protection from, nor constrain the use
and development of, stations of the fixed and mobile services.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J81"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may also be used on a secondary basis by stations
of the fixed service that is closely related to the land mobile service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J82"><![CDATA[ In the bands 435-438MHz, 1260-1270MHz, 2400-2450MHz, and 5650-
5670MHz, the amateur-satellite service may be operated on condition that it does not
cause harmful interference to other services operated in accordance with the Table of
Frequency Allocations of the RR. The use of the bands 1260-1270MHz and
5650- 5670 MHz by the amateur-satellite service is limited to the Earth-to-space
direction.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J83"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by sensors in the Earth exploration-satellite service
(active) shall be in accordance with Recommendation ITU-R SA.1260-1.
Additionally, the Earth exploration-satellite service (active) in the band
432-438 MHz shall not cause harmful interference to the aeronautical 
radionavigation service in China. The provisions of this footnote in no way diminish
the obligation of the Earth exploration-satellite service (active) to operate as a
secondary service in accordance with Nos. 5.29 and 5.30 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J84"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by mobile service shall not claim protection from,
and shall not cause harmful interference to, other stations operating in accordance
with this Frequency Allocation Table.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J85"><![CDATA[ The band 449.75-450.25MHz may be used by the space operation
service (Earth-to-space) and the space research service (Earth-to-space) on condition
that the Japanese administration obtains agreements of other administrations in
accordance with No. 9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J86"><![CDATA[ The allocation of this band to the meteorological-satellite service
(space-to-Earth) is on a primary basis, on condition that the Japanese administration
obtains agreements of other administrations in accordance with No.9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J87"><![CDATA[ The frequency bands 460-470MHz and 1690-1710MHz may be
allocated to the Earth exploration-satellite service (space-to-Earth) except for the
meteorological-satellite service on condition that the use of frequencies does not
cause harmful interference to stations operating in accordance with the Table of
Frequency Allocations of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J88"><![CDATA[ This frequency allocated to the broadcasting services or the
broadcasting-satellite services shall be that stipulated in Article 26, Paragraph 2(5) b),
of the Radio Law.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J89"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the broadcasting service for the
commercial telecommunications service (Area Broadcasting) and the broadcasting
(Area Broadcasting) shall not cause harmful interference to, or claim protection from
the stations of the land mobile service for the broadcast auxiliary service (Specified
Radio Microphone and Digital Specified Radio Microphone) and the general service
(Specified Radio Microphone and Digital Specified Radio Microphone) using the
frequency band 470-710MHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J90"><![CDATA[ The band 608-614MHz is also allocated to the radio astronomy service
on a secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J91"><![CDATA[ Not used.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J92"><![CDATA[ Not used.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J93"><![CDATA[ Until 31 March 2019, stations of the mobile service for the commercial
telecommunications service in this frequency band shall not cause harmful
interference to other stations of the mobile service using this frequency band.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J94"><![CDATA[ This frequency band may be used for the broadcasting services that
provide broadcasting services and commercial telecommunications services as the
secondary purpose stipulated in Article 6, Paragraph 1, of the Radio Law, limited to
stations for the mobile services that provide commercial telecommunications
services as the principal purpose stipulated in the same article. In this case, the
frequency of this frequency band shall be that stipulated in Article 26, paragraph 2(5)
b), of the Radio Law.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J95"><![CDATA[ The use of the frequency band 905-915 MHz and 950-958MHz by
stations of the mobile services for commercial telecommunications services shall not
cause harmful interference to other stations for mobile services using this band until
31 March 2018.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J96"><![CDATA[ The use of the frequency band 958-960 MHz by stations of the mobile
services for commercial telecommunications services shall not cause harmful
interference to stations for fixed services using this band until 30 November 2015.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J97"><![CDATA[ Stations in the radionavigation-satellite service in this band shall
operate in accordance with the provisions of Resolution 609 (Rev.WRC-07) and
shall not claim protection from stations in the aeronautical radionavigation service in
the band 960-1215 MHz. No. 5.43A of the RR does not apply. The provisions of
No. 21.18 of the RR shall apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J98"><![CDATA[ See No.5.328B of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J99"><![CDATA[ Use of the radionavigation-satellite service in this band shall be subject
to the condition that no harmful interference is caused to, and no protection is
claimed from, the radionavigation service authorized under No.5.331 of the RR. See
also Resolution 608 (WRC-03).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J100"><![CDATA[ Use of systems in the radionavigation-satellite service (space-to-space)
operating in the bands 1215-1300MHz and 1559-1610MHz is not intended to
provide safety service applications, and shall not impose any additional constraints
on radionavigation-satellite service (space-to-Earth) systems or on other services
operating in accordance with the Table of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J101"><![CDATA[ In this band, active spaceborne sensors in the Earth exploration-satellite
and space research services shall not cause harmful interference to, claim protection
from, or otherwise impose constraints on operation or development of the
radiolocation service, the radionavigation-satellite service and other services
allocated on a primary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J102"><![CDATA[ In this band, active spaceborne sensors in the Earth exploration-satellite
and space research services shall not cause harmful interference to, claim protection
from, or otherwise impose constraints on operation or development of the
radiolocation service and other services allocated by footnotes on a primary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J103"><![CDATA[ Stations of the mobile service in this frequency band shall not cause
harmful interference to, or claim protection from other stations of co-primary
services using this frequency band.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J104"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the aeronautical radionavigation service is
restricted to ground-based radar and to associating airborne transponders activated
by such radar.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J105"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by earth stations in the radionavigation-satellite
service and by stations in the radiolocation service shall not cause harmful
interference to, nor constrain the operation and development of, the
aeronautical-radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J106"><![CDATA[ The bands 1370-1400MHz, 4950-4990MHz and 15.20-15.35GHz are
also allocated to the space research (passive) and earth exploration-satellite (passive)
services on a secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J107"><![CDATA[ All emissions are prohibited in the following bands. However, this
limitation is eased by stations of UWB radio systems.:
1400-1427MHz,
2690-2700MHz,
15.35-15.4GHz,
23.6-24GHz,
31.3-31.5GHz,
50.2-50.4GHz,
52.6-54.25GHz,
86-92GHz,
100-102GHz,
109.5-111.8GHz,
114.25-116GHz,
148.5-151.5GHz,
164-167GHz,
182-185GHz,
190-191.8GHz,
200-209GHz,
226-231.5GHz,
250-252GHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J108"><![CDATA[ In the jurisdictional districts of Hokkaido Bureau of
Telecommunications, Tohoku Bureau of Telecommunications, Shinetsu Bureau of
Telecommunications, Hokuriku Bureau of Telecommunications, Chugoku Bureau of
Telecommunications, Shikoku Bureau of Telecommunications, Kyushu Bureau of
Telecommunications and Okinawa Office of Telecommunications, the purpose of
radio stations is the commercial telecommunications service. In the jurisdictional
districts of other Bureaus of Telecommunications, the purpose of radio stations is the
general service until 31 March 2014, and the commercial telecommunications
service after 1 April 2014.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J109"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is subject to
coordination under No. 9.11A of the RR. In the band 1518-1525 MHz stations in the
mobile-satellite service shall not claim protection from the stations in the fixed
service. No. 5.43A of the RR does not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J110"><![CDATA[ In this band, the coordination threshold in terms of the power
flux-density levels at the surface of the Earth in application of No. 9.11A of the RR
for space stations in the mobile-satellite (space-to-Earth) service, with respect to the
land mobile service use for specialized mobile radios or used in conjunction with
public switched telecommunication networks (PSTN) operating within the territory
of Japan, shall be –150 dB(W/m2
) in any 4 kHz band for all angles of arrival, instead
of those given in Table 5-2 of Appendix 5 of the RR. In the band 1518-1525 MHz
stations in the mobile-satellite service shall not claim protection from stations in the
mobile service in the territory of Japan. No. 5.43A of the RR does not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J111"><![CDATA[ In this band, stations in the mobile-satellite service shall not claim
protection from aeronautical mobile telemetry stations in the mobile service in the
territory of the United States (see No. 5.343 and 5.344 of the RR) and in the
countries listed in No. 5.342 of the RR. No. 5.43A of the RR does not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J112"><![CDATA[ For the use of the bands 1518-1544MHz, 1545-1559MHz, 1610-1645.5 
MHz, 1646.5-1660.5MHz, 1668-1675MHz, 1980-2010MHz, 2170-2200MHz,
2483.5-2520MHz and 2670-2690MHz by the mobile-satellite service, see
Resolutions 212 (Rev.WRC-07) and 225 (Rev.WRC-07)..
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J113"><![CDATA[ In this band, stations of the mobile-satellite service, except for the
stations of the maritime mobile-satellite service, shall not cause harmful interference,
or claim any protections to the stations of the fixed service operating in the countries
and territories listed on No.5.352A of the RR notified prior to 1 April 1998.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J114"><![CDATA[ The bands 1525-1544MHz, 1545-1559MHz, 1626.5-1645.5MHz and
1646.5-1660.5MHz shall not be used for feeder links of any service. In exceptional
circumstances, however, an earth station at a specified fixed point in any of the
mobile-satellite services may be authorized.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J115"><![CDATA[ The use of the bands 1525-1559MHz and 1626.5-1660.5MHz by the
mobile-satellite services is subject to coordination under No.9.11A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J116"><![CDATA[ In applying the procedures of Section II of Article 9 to the
mobile-satellite service in the bands 1530-1544MHz and 1626.5-1645.5MHz,
priority shall be given to accommodating the spectrum requirements for distress,
urgency and safety communications of the Global Maritime Distress and Safety
System (GMDSS). Maritime mobile-satellite distress, urgency and safety
communications shall have priority access and immediate availability over all other
mobile satellite communications operating within a network. Mobile-satellite
systems shall not cause unacceptable interference to, or claim protection from,
distress, urgency and safety communications of the GMDSS. Account shall be taken
of the priority of safety-related communications in the other mobile-satellite services.
(The provisions of Resolution 222 (Rev.WRC-12) shall apply.)
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J117"><![CDATA[ The use of the band 1544-1545MHz by the mobile-satellite service
(space-to-Earth) is limited to distress and safety communications.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J118"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service (Earth-to-space) and
inter-satellite links is limited to distress and safety communications.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J119"><![CDATA[ Transmissions in this band from terrestrial aeronautical stations directly
to aircraft stations, or between aircraft stations, in the aeronautical mobile (R)
service are also authorized when such transmissions are used to extend or
supplement the satellite-to-aircraft links.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J120"><![CDATA[ In applying the procedures of Section II of Article 9 of the RR to the
mobile-satellite service in the bands 1545-1555MHz and 1646.5-1656.5MHz,
priority shall be given to accommodating the spectrum requirements of the
aeronautical mobile-satellite (R) service providing transmission of messages with
priority 1 to 6 in Article 44 of the RR. Aeronautical mobile-satellite (R) service
communications with priority 1 to 6 in Article 44 of the RR shall have priority
access and immediate availability, by pre-emption if necessary, over all other
mobile-satellite communications operating within a network. Mobile-satellite
systems shall not cause unacceptable interference to, or claim protection from,
aeronautical mobile-satellite (R) service communications with priority 1 to 6 in
Article 44 of the RR. Account shall be taken of the priority of safety-related
communications in the other mobile-satellite services. (The provisions of Resolution
222 (WRC-2000) shall apply.)
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J121"><![CDATA[ This band is reserved on a worldwide basis for the use and development
of airborne electronic aids to air navigation and any directly associated ground-based
or satellite-borne facilities. Such satellite use is subject to agreement obtained from
other administrations under No. 9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J122"><![CDATA[ This band is also allocated to the aeronautical mobile-satellite (R)
service on a primary basis, subject to agreement obtained from other administrations
under No.9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J123"><![CDATA[ With respect to the radiodetermination-satellite and mobile-satellite
service, the provisions of No.4.10 of the RR do not apply in this band, with the
exception of the aeronautical radionavigation-satellite service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J124"><![CDATA[ The use of the band 1610-1626.5MHz by the mobile-satellite service
(Earth-to-space) and by the radiodetermination-satellite service (Earth-to-space) is
subject to coordination under No.9.11A of the RR. A mobile earth station operating
in either of the services in this band shall not produce a peak equivalent isotropic
radiated power (e.i.r.p.) density in excess of -15dB(W/4 kHz) in the part of the band
used by systems operating in accordance with the provisions of No. 5.366 of the RR
(to which No. 4.10 of the RR applies), unless otherwise agreed to by the affected
administrations. In the part of the band where such systems are not operating, the
mean e.i.r.p., density of a mobile earth station shall not exceed -3dB(W/4 kHz).
Stations of the mobile-satellite service shall not claim protection from stations of the
aeronautical radionavigation service, stations operating in accordance with the
provisions of No.5.366 of the RR and stations of the fixed service operating in
accordance with the provisions of No.5.359 of the RR. 

   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J125"><![CDATA[ Stations of the radiodetermination-satellite service shall not cause
harmful interference to stations of the radio astronomy service that are using the
band 1610.6- 1613.8MHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J126"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service (space-to-Earth) is
subject to coordination under No.9.11A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J127"><![CDATA[ Mobile earth stations of the mobile-satellite service operating in the
bands 1631.5-1634.5MHz and 1656.5-1660MHz shall not cause harmful
interference to stations of the fixed service operating in the countries listed on
No.5.359 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J128"><![CDATA[ Transmissions in this band from aircraft stations of the aeronautical
mobile (R) service directly to terrestrial aeronautical stations, or between aircraft
stations, are also authorized when such transmissions are used to extend or
supplement the aircraft-to-satellite links.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J129"><![CDATA[ Mobile earth stations operating in this band shall not cause harmful
interference to stations of the radio astronomy service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J130"><![CDATA[ For sharing of this band between the mobile-satellite service and the
fixed, mobile and space research (passive) services, Resolution 744 (Rev.WRC-07)
shall apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J131"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite service is subject to
coordination under No. 9.11A of the RR. In the band 1668-1668.4MHz, Resolution
904 (WRC-07) shall apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J132"><![CDATA[ In order to protect the radio astronomy service in this band, the
aggregate power flux-density values produced by mobile earth stations in a network
of the mobile-satellite service operating in this band shall not exceed
–181 dB(W/m2
) in 10 MHz and 194 dB(W/m2
) in any 20 kHz at any radio
astronomy station recorded in the Master International Frequency Register, for more
than 2% of integration periods of 2000 s.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J133"><![CDATA[ In this band, stations in the mobile-satellite service shall not cause
harmful interference to stations in the meteorological aids service operating in the
countries listed on No.5.379 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J134"><![CDATA[ See No.5.328B of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J135"><![CDATA[ The band 1750-1850MHz is also allocated to the space operation
(Earth-to-space) and space research (Earth-to-space) services on a primary basis,
subject to agreements obtained from other administrations under No.9.21 of the RR,
having particular regard to troposcatter systems.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J136"><![CDATA[ This band may be also used International Mobile Telecommunications
(IMT) in accordance with Resolution 223 (Rev.WRC-07).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J137"><![CDATA[ The bands 1885-2025MHz and 2110-2200MHz are intended for use by
International Mobile Telecommunications (IMT). The bands should be made
available for IMT in accordance with Resolution 212 (Rev.WRC-97). (See also
Resolution 223 (WRC-2000).)
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J138"><![CDATA[ The bands 1885-1980MHz, 2010-2025MHz and 2110-2170MHz may
be used by high altitude platform stations as base stations to provide IMT-2000, in
accordance with Resolution 221 (Rev.WRC-03).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J139"><![CDATA[ For the purpose of protecting fixed and mobile services operating in the
countries listed on No.5.388B of the RR, including IMT-2000 mobile stations, in
their territories from co-channel interference, a high altitude platform station
(HAPS) operating as an IMT-2000 base station in neighbouring countries, in the
bands referred to in No. 5.388A of the RR, shall not exceed a co-channel power
flux-density of -127 dB(W/(m2
· MHz)) at the Earth’s surface outside a country’s
borders unless explicit agreement of the affected administration is provided at the
time of the notification of HAPS.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J140"><![CDATA[ The use of the bands 1980-2 010MHz and 2170-2 200MHz by the
mobile-satellite service is subject to coordination under No.9.11A of the RR and to
the provisions of Resolution 716 (Rev.WRC-2000).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J141"><![CDATA[ In making assignments to the mobile service in the bands
2025-2110MHz and 2200-2290MHz, high-density mobile systems shall not be
introduced, as described in SA.1154 of the Recommendation ITU-R, and this
recommendation shall be taken into account for the introduction of any other type of
mobile system.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J142"><![CDATA[ All practicable measures shall be taken to ensure that space-to-space
transmission between two or more non-geostationary satellites, in the space research,
space operations and the Earth exploration-satellite service in the bands
2025-2110MHz and 2200-2290MHz, shall not impose any constraints on 
Earth-to-space, space-to-Earth and other space-to-space transmissions of those
services and in those bands between geostationary and non-geostationary satellites.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J143"><![CDATA[ In regard to the radiodetermination-satellite service in this band, the
provisions of No.4.10 of the RR do not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J144"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the mobile-satellite and the
radiodetermination-satellite services is subject to the coordination under No.9.11A of
the RR. All practicable steps shall be taken to prevent harmful interference to the
radio astronomy service from emissions in this band, especially those caused by
second-harmonic radiation that would fall into the 4990-5000MHz band allocated to
the radio astronomy service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J145"><![CDATA[ The allocation of the frequency band 2500-2520MHz to the
mobile-satellite service (space-to-Earth) is subject to coordination under No.9.11A of
the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J146"><![CDATA[ The band 2515-2535MHz may also be used by the aeronautical
mobile-satellite service (space-to-Earth) for operation limited to within Japan subject
to agreement obtained from other administrations under No.9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J147"><![CDATA[ Subject to agreement obtained from other administrations under
No.9.21 of the RR, the band 2520-2535MHz may also be used by the
mobile-satellite (space-to-Earth) service except for the aeronautical mobile-satellite
service, for operation limited to within Japan. The provisions of No. 9.11A of the
RR apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J148"><![CDATA[ The use of the band 2545-2555MHz by the stations in the mobile service
shall not cause harmful interference to the mobile-satellite service in the band
2505-2535 MHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J149"><![CDATA[ The band 2655-2670MHz may also be used by the mobile-satellite
(Earth-to-space) service except for the aeronautical mobile-satellite service, for
operation only within Japan, subject to agreement obtained from other
administrations under No.9.21 of the RR. The provisions of No. 9.11A of the RR
apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J150"><![CDATA[ Introducing systems of the mobile-satellite service in this band shall
take all necessary steps to protect the satellite systems operating in this band prior to
3 March 1992. The coordination of mobile-satellite systems in the band shall be in
accordance with No.9.11A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J151"><![CDATA[ In this band, ground-based radars used for meteorological purposes are
authorized to operate on a primary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J152"><![CDATA[ In this band, the use of the shipboard interrogator-transponder system
(SIT) shall be confined to the sub-bands 2930 -2950MHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J153"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the aeronautical radionavigation service is
limited to ground-based radar.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J154"><![CDATA[ The frequency bands 2920-3100MHz and 9320-9500MHz may not be
used by radarbeacons (racons) that use fixed-frequencies of the maritime
radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J155"><![CDATA[ In this band, stations in the radiolocation service shall not cause harmful
interference to, nor claim protection from, radar systems in the radionavigation
service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J156"><![CDATA[ The frequency band 3100-3266MHz may also be used by radarbeacons
and radars that are used for ships.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J157"><![CDATA[ See No.5.432A and 5.433A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J158"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the broadcasting-satellite service
(domestic and overseas broadcasting) is restricted to cases where the operation will
not cause harmful interference to stations operating in accordance with the Table of
Frequency Allocations in the RR. Stations of the broadcasting-satellite service
(domestic and overseas broadcasting) shall not claim protection from stations
operating in accordance with the Table.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J159"><![CDATA[ The standard frequency and time signal-satellite service for
space-to-Earth transmissions may be authorized to use the frequency band
4200-4204MHz, subject to agreement obtained from other administrations under
No.9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J160"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the aeronautical radionavigation
service is reserved exclusively for radio altimeters installed on board aircraft and for
the associated transponders on the ground. However, passive sensing in the
Earth-exploration-satellites and space research services may be authorized in this
band on a secondary basis (no protection is provided from the radio altimeters).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J161"><![CDATA[ See No.5.441 of the RR.
- 68 -
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J162"><![CDATA[ In the bands 4825-4835 MHz and 4950-4990 MHz, the allocation to the
mobile service is restricted to the mobile, except aeronautical mobile, service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J163"><![CDATA[ In the frequency bands 5000-5030MHz and 5091-5150MHz, the
aeronautical mobile-satellite (R) service is subject to agreement obtained under No.
9.21. The use of these bands by the aeronautical mobile-satellite (R) service is
limited to internationally standardized aeronautical systems.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J164"><![CDATA[ In order not to cause harmful interference to the microwave landing
system operating above 5030 MHz, the aggregate power flux-density produced at the
Earth’s surface in the band 5030-5150 MHz by all the space stations within any
radionavigation-satellite service system (space-to-Earth) operating in the band
5010-5030 MHz shall not exceed –124.5 dB(W/m2
) in a 150 kHz band. In order not
to cause harmful interference to the radio astronomy service in the band 4990-5000
MHz, radionavigation-satellite service systems operating in the band
5010-5030 MHz shall comply with the limits in the band 4990-5000 MHz defined in
Resolution 741 (Rev.WRC-12).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J165"><![CDATA[ This frequency band is also allocated to the Wireless Access System in
the 5GHz band in the mobile service. An assignment to the Wireless Access System
in the 5GHz band is subject to Annex 6-3-8, and the use of this frequency band for
the Wireless Access System in the 5GHz band is allowed only until 30 November
2017.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J166"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the aeronautical mobile service is limited
to:
– systems operating in the aeronautical mobile (R) service and in accordance
with international aeronautical standards, limited to surface applications at
airports. Such use shall be in accordance with Resolution 748
(Rev.WRC-12);
– aeronautical telemetry transmissions from aircraft stations (see No. 1.83) in
accordance with Resolution 418 (Rev.WRC-12);
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J167"><![CDATA[ See No.5.444A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J168"><![CDATA[ The allocation to the fixed-satellite service (Earth-to-space) is limited to
feeder links of non-geostationary mobile-satellite systems in the mobile-satellite
service and is subject to coordination under No. 9.11A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J169"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the aeronautical mobile (R) service is
limited to internationally standardized aeronautical systems. Until such time that an
appropriate value is established in a relevant ITU-R Recommendation, the e.i.r.p.
density limit of -75 dBW/MHz in this frequency band for any AM(R)S station
unwanted emission should be used.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J170"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the aeronautical mobile-satellite (R)
service is subject to coordination under No. 9.11A, and is limited to internationally
standardized aeronautical systems.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J171"><![CDATA[ This frequency band is also allocated to the mobile service on a primary
basis, subject to agreement obtained from other administrations under No.9.21 of the
RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J172"><![CDATA[ The band 5150-5216MHz is also allocated to the
radiodetermination-satellite service (space-to-Earth) on a secondary basis. The use by
the radiodetermination-satellite service is limited to feeder links in conjunction with the
radiodetermination-satellite service operating in the bands 1610-1626.5MHz and
2483.5-2500MHz. The total power flux-density at the Earth’s surface shall in no case
exceed -159dBW/m2
/4 kHz for all angles of arrival.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J173"><![CDATA[ The use of the bands 5150-5350 MHz and 5470-5650 MHz by the
stations in the mobile service, except aeronautical mobile, shall be in accordance
with Resolution 229 (Rev.WRC-12).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J174"><![CDATA[ In the band 5150-5250 MHz, stations in the mobile service shall not
claim protection from earth stations in the fixed-satellite service. No. 5.43A of the
RR does not apply to the mobile service with respect to fixed-satellite service earth
stations.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J175"><![CDATA[ The band 5150-5650 MHz may also be used by Low-Power Data
Transmission System in the mobile service in the airplane. In addition, the use of the
band 5150-5350 MHz is restricted to place where indoor or indoor and an equal
cover effect are accepted.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J176"><![CDATA[ The Earth exploration-satellite (active) and space research (active)
services in this frequency band shall not claim protection from the radiolocation
service. No. 5.43A of the RR does not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J177"><![CDATA[ The allocation of this frequency band to the space research service on a 
primary basis is limited to active spaceborne sensors. Other uses of this band by the
space research service are on a secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J178"><![CDATA[ This frequency band is also allocated to the fixed service on a primary
basis. The use of this band by the fixed service is intended for the implementation of
fixed wireless access systems and shall comply with Recommendation ITU-R
F.1613. In addition, the fixed service shall not claim protection from the radiodetermination,
Earth exploration-satellite (active) and space research (active)
services, but the provisions of No. 5.43A of the RR do not apply to the fixed service
with respect to the Earth exploration-satellite (active) and space research (active)
services. After implementation of fixed wireless access systems in the fixed service
with protection for the existing radiodetermination systems, no more stringent
constraints should be imposed on the fixed wireless access systems by future
radiodetermination implementations.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J179"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, stations in the mobile service shall not claim
protection from the radiolocation service, the Earth exploration-satellite service
(active) and the space research service (active). These services shall not impose on
the mobile service more stringent protection criteria, based on system characteristics
and interference criteria, than those stated in Recommendations ITU-R M.1638 and
ITU-R SA.1632.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J180"><![CDATA[ The Earth exploration-satellite service (active) operating in the band
5350-5570 MHz and space research service (active) operating in the band 5460-5570
MHz shall not cause harmful interference to the aeronautical radionavigation service
in the band 5350-5460 MHz, the radionavigation service in the band
5460-5470 MHz and the maritime radionavigation service in the band
5470-5570 MHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J181"><![CDATA[ The space research service (active) operating in the band 5350-5460
MHz shall not cause harmful interference to nor claim protection from other services
to which this band is allocated.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J182"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, stations in the radiolocation service shall not
cause harmful interference to, nor claim protection from, radar systems in the
aeronautical radionavigation service operating in accordance with No. 5.449 of the
RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J183"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, stations in the mobile service shall not claim
protection from radiodetermination services. Radiodetermination services shall not
impose on the mobile service more stringent protection criteria, based on system
characteristics and interference criteria, than those stated in Recommendation
ITU-R M.1638.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J184"><![CDATA[ Stations in the radiolocation service, except ground-based radars used
for meteorological purposes in the band 5600-5650 MHz, shall not cause harmful
interference to, nor claim protection from, radar systems in the maritime
radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J185"><![CDATA[ The frequency band 5830-5 850MHz may also be used on a secondary
basis by the amateur-satellite service (space-to-Earth).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J186"><![CDATA[ In the bands 5925-6425 MHz and 14-14.5 GHz, portable mobile earth
station established under Article 49.24.2 of Ordinance Regulating Radio Equipment
located on board vessels may communicate with space stations of the fixed-satellite
service. Such use shall be in accordance with Resolution 902 (WRC-03). In this case,
“earth station located on board vessels” in this Resolution is transported to “portable
mobile earth station established under Article 49.24.2 of Ordinance Regulating
Radio Equipment”.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J187"><![CDATA[ The standard frequency and time signal-satellite service for
Earth-to-space transmissions may be authorized to use the frequency band
6425-6429MHz, subject to agreement obtained from other administrations under
No.9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J188"><![CDATA[ The use of the band 7145-7190 MHz by the space research service
(Earth-to-space) is restricted to deep space; no emissions to deep space shall be
effected in the band 7190-7235 MHz. Geostationary satellites in the space research
service operating in the band 7190-7235 MHz shall not claim protection from
existing and future stations of the fixed and mobile services and No. 5.43A of the RR
does not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J189"><![CDATA[ The band 7250-7375MHz is also allocated to the mobile-satellite
(space-to-Earth) service on a primary basis, subject to agreement obtained from
other administrations under No.9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J189"><![CDATA[A The frequency band 7375-7425MHz may also be used on a secondary
basis by stations of the mobile-satellite service (space-to-Earth) that is closely
related to the fixed-satellite service (space-to-Earth).
- 70 -
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J189"><![CDATA[B The frequency band may also be used on a secondary basis by stations
of the mobile-satellite service (space-to-Earth) that is closely related to the
fixed-satellite service (space-to-Earth).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J190"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the meteorological-satellite service
(space-to-Earth) is limited to non-geostationary-satellite systems.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J191"><![CDATA[ This band is also allocated to the mobile-satellite (Earth-to-space)
service on a primary basis, subject to agreement obtained from other administrations
under No.9.21 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J191"><![CDATA[A The frequency band may also be used on a secondary basis by stations
of the mobile-satellite service (Earth-to-space) that is closely related to the
fixed-satellite service (Earth-to-space).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J192"><![CDATA[ In the space research service, the use of the band 8400-8450MHz is
limited to deep space.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J193"><![CDATA[ In this band, stations of the Earth exploration-satellite service (active)
and the space research service (active) shall not cause harmful interference to, or
constrain the use and development of, stations of the radiolocation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J194"><![CDATA[ In the bands 8850-9000MHz and 9200-9225MHz, the maritime
radionavigation service is limited to shore-based radar.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J195"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, stations operating in the radiolocation service
shall not cause harmful interference to, nor claim protection from, systems identified
in No. 5.337 of the RR operating in the aeronautical radionavigation service, or radar
systems in the maritime radionavigation service operating in this band on a primary
basis in the countries listed in No. 5.471 of the RR..
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J196"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the aeronautical radionavigation service is
limited to airborne weather radar and ground-based radar. In addition, ground-based
radar beacons of the aeronautical radionavigation service are permitted on condition
that harmful interference is not caused to the maritime radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J197"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the Earth exploration-satellite service
(active) and the space research service (active) is limited to systems requiring
necessary bandwidth greater than 300 MHz that cannot be fully accommodated
within the 9500-9800 MHz band.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J198"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, stations operating in the radiolocation service
shall not cause harmful interference to, nor claim protection from, radars operating
in the radionavigation service in conformity with the Radio Regulations.
Ground-based radars used for meteorological purposes have priority over other
radiolocation stations.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J199"><![CDATA[ In this band, stations of the Earth exploration-satellite service (active)
and the space research service (active) shall not cause harmful interference to, nor
claim protection from, stations of the radionavigation and the radiolocation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J200"><![CDATA[ The use of the band 9800-9900 MHz by the Earth exploration-satellite
service (active) and the space research service (active) is limited to systems requiring
necessary bandwidth greater than 500 MHz that cannot be fully accommodated
within the 9300-9800 MHz band.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J201"><![CDATA[ In the band 9800-9900 MHz, stations in the Earth exploration-satellite
service (active) and space research service (active) shall not cause harmful
interference to, nor claim protection from stations of the fixed service to which this
band is allocated on a secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J202"><![CDATA[ The band 9975-10025MHz is also allocated to the
meteorological-satellite service on a secondary basis for use by weather radar.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J203"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band is restricted to cases in which operation
does not cause harmful interference to the foreign radio stations whose service is
except the amateur service and amateur-satellite service operating in accordance
with the Table of Frequency Allocations of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J204"><![CDATA[ This frequency band is also allocated to the fixed-satellite service
(space-to-Earth) on a primary basis, limited to non-geostationary systems.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J205"><![CDATA[ Assignments to stations of the broadcasting-satellite service in
conformity with the appropriate regional plan in Appendix 30 of the RR, may also be
used for transmissions in the fixed-satellite service (space-to-Earth), provided that
such transmissions do not cause more interference or require more protection from
interference than the broadcasting-satellite service transmissions operating in
conformity with this plan. With respect to the space services, this band shall be used
principally for the broadcasting-satellite service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J206"><![CDATA[ The use of the bands 10.95-11.2GHz (space-to-Earth), 11.45-11.7GHz 
(space-to-Earth), 12.2-12.75GHz (space-to-Earth), 13.75-14.5GHz (Earth-to-space),
17.8-18.6GHz (space-to-Earth), 19.7-20.2GHz (space-to-Earth), 27.5-28.6GHz
(Earth-to-space), 29.5-30GHz (Earth-to-space) by a non-geostationary-satellite
system in the fixed-satellite service is subject to application of the provisions of No.
9.12 for coordination with other non-geostationary-satellite systems in the
fixed-satellite service. Non-geostationary-satellite systems in the fixed-satellite
service shall not claim protection from geostationary-satellite networks in the
fixed-satellite service operating in accordance with the Radio Regulations,
irrespective of the dates of receipt by the Bureau of the complete coordination or
notification information, as appropriate, for the non-geostationary-satellite systems
in the fixed-satellite service and of the complete coordination or notification
information, as appropriate, for the geostationary-satellite networks, and No. 5.43A
of the RR does not apply. Non-geostationary-satellite systems in the fixed-satellite
service in the above bands shall be operated in such a way that any unacceptable
interference that may occur during their operation shall be rapidly eliminated.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J207"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, aircraft earth stations in the secondary
aeronautical mobile-satellite service may also communicate with space stations in
the fixed-satellite service. The provisions of Nos. 5.29, 5.30 and 5.31 of the RR
apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J208"><![CDATA[ In the band 12.2-12.44GHz, VSAT Earth station shall not claim
protection to the harmful interference from stations of the fixed service which is
operated in the frequency band.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J209"><![CDATA[ The Earth exploration-satellite (active) and the space research (active)
services operating in this frequency band shall not cause harmful interference to, or
constrain the use and development of, the aeronautical radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J210"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the aeronautical radionavigation
service is limited to Doppler navigation aids.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J211"><![CDATA[ The allocation of this frequency band to the space research service on a
primary basis is limited to active spaceborne sensors. Other uses of the band by the
space research service are on a secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J212"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the Earth exploration-satellite
(active) and the space research (active) services shall not cause harmful interference
to, or constrain the use and development of, the radiolocation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J213"><![CDATA[ See No.5.502 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J214"><![CDATA[ See No.5.503 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J215"><![CDATA[ See No.5.506A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J216"><![CDATA[ See No.5.511D of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J217"><![CDATA[ See No.5.511A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J218"><![CDATA[ Stations of the aeronautical radionavigation service shall limit the
effective equivalent isotropic radiated power (e.i.r.p.) in accordance with
Recommendation ITU-R S.1340. The minimum coordination distance required to
protect the aeronautical radionavigation stations (limited to the stations that are
applied No. 4.10 of the RR) from harmful interference from feeder link earth stations
and the maximum e.i.r.p. transmitted towards the local horizontal plane by a feeder
link earth station shall be in accordance with Recommendation ITU-R S.1340.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J219"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, stations operating in the radiolocation service
shall not cause harmful interference to, or claim protection from, stations operating
in the aeronautical radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J220"><![CDATA[ In order to protect the radio astronomy service in the frequency band
15.35-15.4 GHz, radiolocation stations operating in the frequency band 15.4-15.7
GHz shall not exceed the power flux-density level of -156dB(W/m2
) in a 50 MHz
bandwidth in the frequency band 15.35-15.4 GHz, at any radio astronomy
observatory site for more than 2 per cent of the time.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J221"><![CDATA[ Spaceborne active sensors operating in this frequency band shall not
cause harmful interference to, or constrain the development of, the radiolocation and
other services allocated on a primary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J222"><![CDATA[ The use of the band 17.3-18.1GHz and 18.1-18.4GHz by the
fixed-satellite service (Earth-to-space) is limited to feeder links for the
broadcasting-satellite service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J223"><![CDATA[ This frequency band is also allocated to the meteorological-satellite
service (space-to-Earth) on a primary basis. Its use is limited to
geostationary-satellites.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J224"><![CDATA[ The emissions of the fixed service and the fixed-satellite service in this 
- 72 -
frequency band are limited to the values given in Nos. 21.5A and 21.16.2 of the RR,
respectively.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J225"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the fixed-satellite service is limited to
geostationary systems and systems with an orbit of apogee greater than 20000 km.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J226"><![CDATA[ See No.5.523A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J227"><![CDATA[ The use of the band 19.3-19.6GHz by the fixed-satellite service
(Earth-to-space) is limited to feeder links for non-geostationary systems of the
mobile-satellite service. Such use is subject to the application of the provisions of
No.9.11A of the RR, and No.22.2 of the RR does not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J228"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band (space-to-Earth) by geostationary
fixed-satellite service systems and by feeder links for non-geostationary-satellite
systems of the mobile-satellite service is subject to the application of the provisions
of No.9.11A of the RR, but not subject to the provisions of No.22.2 of the RR. The
use of this band by other non-geostationary fixed-satellite service systems, or the
cases indicated in Nos.5.523C and 5.523E of the RR; however, this use shall
continue to be subject to the procedures of Articles 9 (except No.9.11A) and 11 of
the RR, as well as to the provisions of No.22.2 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J229"><![CDATA[ See No.5.523C of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J230"><![CDATA[ See No.5.523E of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J231"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the fixed or the mobile services shall
not impose any limitation on the power flux-density of space stations of the
fixed-satellite service and of space stations of the mobile-satellite service operating
in the band 19.7-20.2GHz, which is allocated to the mobile-satellite service is on a
primary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J232"><![CDATA[ The bands 19.7-20.2GHz (space-to-Earth), 28.45-29.1GHz
(Earth-to-space), 29.46-30GHz (Earth-to-space) and 40-40.5GHz (space-to-Earth)
are identified for use by high-density applications in the fixed-satellite service
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J233"><![CDATA[ In order to facilitate interregional coordination between networks of the
mobile-satellite and the fixed-satellite services, carriers of the mobile-satellite
service that are most susceptible to interference shall, to the maximum extent
practicable, be assigned in the higher parts of the bands 19.7-20.2GHz and
29.5-30GHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J234"><![CDATA[ In the bands 19.7-20.2GHz and 29.5-30GHz, the provisions of 4.10 of
the RR do not apply with respect to the mobile-satellite service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J235"><![CDATA[ In the bands 20.1-20.2GHz and 29.9-30.0GHz, networks which are both
in the fixed-satellite service and in the mobile-satellite service may include links
between earth stations at specified or unspecified points or while in motion, through
one or more satellites for point-to-point and point-to-multi-point communications.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J236"><![CDATA[ The allocation to the mobile-satellite service is intended to be used by
networks that use narrow spot-beam antennas and other advanced technology on
space stations. In operating the mobile-satellite service systems in this frequency
band, all practicable steps shall be taken to ensure the continued availability of the
bands assigned to fixed and mobile systems in accordance with the provisions of
No.5.524 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J237"><![CDATA[ Unless otherwise agreed between the administrations concerned, any
station in the fixed or mobile services shall not produce a power flux-density in
excess of -120.4 dB(W/(m2
· MHz)) at 3 m above the ground of any point of the
territory of any other administration for more than 20% of the time. In conducting
the calculations, Recommendation ITU-R P.452 (see Recommendation ITU-R
BO.1898) should be used.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J238"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, in order to facilitate the development of the
broadcasting-satellite service, the deployment of stations of the fixed service and the
mobile service can be limited.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J239"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band is subject to the provisions of Resolution
755 (WRC-12).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J240"><![CDATA[ See Resolution 555 (WRC-12).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J241"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the Earth exploration-satellite (passive) and the
space research (passive) services shall not impose constraints upon the fixed and the
mobile services.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J242"><![CDATA[ The location of earth stations in the space research service shall
maintain a separation distance of at least 54 km from the respective border(s) of
neighbouring countries to protect the existing and future deployment of fixed and
mobile services unless a shorter distance is otherwise agreed between the
corresponding administrations. Nos. 9.17 and 9.18 do not apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J243"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by the fixed-satellite service
(Earth-to-space) is limited to earth stations using a minimum antenna diameter of 4.5
m.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J244"><![CDATA[ The inter-satellite service to which this band is allocated shall not claim
protection from harmful interference from airport surface detection equipment
stations of the radionavigation service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J245"><![CDATA[ In this band, feeder links to stations of the broadcasting-satellite service
shall have priority over other uses of the fixed-satellite service (Earth-to-space).
Such other uses shall not cause interference to and shall not claim protection from
existing and planned feeder link networks of the satellite basic broadcast stations.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J246"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the inter-satellite service is limited to the space
research and the Earth exploration-satellite applications, and to transmissions of data
originating from industrial and medical activities in space.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J247"><![CDATA[ Earth stations in the Earth exploration-satellite service or the space
research service shall not claim protection from stations in the fixed and mobile
services operated by other administrations. In addition, earth stations in the Earth
exploration-satellite service or in the space research service should be operated
taking into account Recommendations ITU-R SA.1862.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J248"><![CDATA[ Space services using non-geostationary-satellites operating in the
inter-satellite service in this frequency band are exempt from the provisions of
No.22.2 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J249"><![CDATA[ This band may be used by the fixed-satellite service (Earth-to-space) for
the provision of feeder links for the broadcasting-satellite service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J250"><![CDATA[ The bands 27.500-27.501GHz and 29.999-30.000GHz are also allocated
to the fixed-satellite service (space-to-Earth) on a primary basis for the beacon
transmissions intended for up-link power control. Such space-to-Earth transmissions
shall not exceed an equivalent isotropic radiated power (e.i.r.p.) of +10dBW in the
direction of adjacent satellites on the geostationary-satellite orbit.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J251"><![CDATA[ The band 27.501-29.999GHz is also allocated to the fixed-satellite
service (space-to-Earth) on a secondary basis for beacon transmissions intended for
up-link power control.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J252"><![CDATA[ The allocation to the fixed service in the band 27.9-28.2 GHz may also
be assigned to high altitude platform stations (HAPS). The use of this frequency
band by HAPS is the auxiliary frequency band. The use of this frequency band
allocated to HAPS is further limited to operation in the HAPS-to-ground direction
and shall not cause harmful interference to, nor claim protection from, other types of
fixed-service systems or other co-primary services. Furthermore, the development of
these other services shall not be constrained by HAPS. See Resolution 145
(Rev.WRC-07).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J253"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, the Earth exploration-satellite service is limited
to the data transfer between stations and not to the primary collection of information
by means of active or passive sensors.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J254"><![CDATA[ See No.5.535A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J255"><![CDATA[ See No.5.541 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J256"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency by the fixed and the mobile services shall be
subject to the power limits specified in Nos. 21.3 and 21.5 of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J257"><![CDATA[ The band 29.95-30GHz may be used for space-to-space links of the
Earth exploration-satellite service for telemetry, tracking, and control purposes, on a
secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J258"><![CDATA[ See No.5.543A of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J259"><![CDATA[ In this band, the power flux-density limits specified in Article 21, Table
21-4 of the RR shall apply to the space research service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J260"><![CDATA[ The bands 31.8-33.4 GHz, 37-40 GHz, 40.5-43.5 GHz, 51.4-52.6 GHz,
55.78-59 GHz and 64-66 GHz are available for high-density applications in the fixed
service (see Resolutions 75 (WRC-2000)).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J261"><![CDATA[ The potential interference between stations in the fixed service and
airborne stations in the radionavigation service in this frequency band should be
minimized, taking into account the operational needs of the airborne radar systems.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J262"><![CDATA[ In designing systems for the inter-satellite service in the band 32.3-33
GHz, for the radionavigation service in the band 32-33 GHz, and for the space
research service (deep space) in the band 31.8-32.3 GHz, administrations shall take
all necessary measures to prevent harmful interference between these services,
bearing in mind the safety aspects of the radionavigation service (see Recommendation 707).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J263"><![CDATA[ In the band 35.5-36.0 GHz, the mean power flux-density at the Earth’s
surface, generated by any spaceborne sensor in the Earth exploration-satellite service
(active) or space research service (active), for any angle greater than 0.8° from the
beam centre shall not exceed 73.3 dB(W/m2
) in this band.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J264"><![CDATA[ For sharing of the band 36-37 GHz between the Earth
exploration-satellite (passive) service and the fixed and mobile services, Resolution
752 (WRC-07) shall apply.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J265"><![CDATA[ See No.5.551H of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J266"><![CDATA[ See No.5.551I of the RR.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J267"><![CDATA[ In the bands 43.5-47GHz and 66-71GHz, stations of the land mobile
service may be operated on condition that harmful interference is not caused to the
space radiocommunication services to which these bands are allocated (see No.5.43
of the RR).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J268"><![CDATA[ In this band, satellite links connecting land stations at specified fixed
points are also authorized when used in conjunction with the mobile-satellite service
or the radionavigation-satellite service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J269"><![CDATA[ All practicable steps shall be taken to reserve the band 47.2-49.2GHz
for feeder links for the broadcasting-satellite service operating in the band
40.5-42.5GHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J270"><![CDATA[ The allocation to the fixed service in the bands 47.2-47.5GHz and
47.9-48.2GHz is designated for use by high altitude platform stations. The use of the
bands 47.2-47.5GHz and 47.9-48.2GHz is subject to the provisions of Resolution
122 (Rev. WRC-07).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J271"><![CDATA[ The band 48.94-49.04GHz is also allocated to the radio astronomy
service on a primary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J272"><![CDATA[ The bands 51.4 - 54.25GHz, 58.2 - 59GHz and 64 - 65GHz may be used
by the radio astronomy service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J273"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band for mobile services (except for the
unlicensed low-power service) is allowed only until 31 December 2021.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J274"><![CDATA[ The use of the bands 54.25-56.9GHz, 57-58.2GHz and 59-59.3GHz by
the inter-satellite service is limited to satellites on the geostationary-satellite orbit.
The single-entry power flux-density at all altitudes from 0km to 1000km above the
Earth's surface produced by a station in the inter-satellite service, for all conditions
and for all methods of modulation, shall not exceed -147dBW/m2
/100 MHz for all
angles of arrival.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J275"><![CDATA[ This frequency band is also allocated to the mobile service on a primary
basis for low-density use.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J276"><![CDATA[ In the band 55.78-56.26GHz, in order to protect stations in the Earth
exploration-satellite service (passive), the maximum power density delivered by a
transmitter to the antenna of a fixed service station is limited to –26dB(W/MHz).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J277"><![CDATA[ In this band, stations of the aeronautical mobile service may be operated
on condition that harmful interference is not caused to the inter-satellite service (see
No.5.43 of the RR).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J278"><![CDATA[ The use of this frequency band by inter-satellite systems is limited to
links between satellites on geostationary-satellite orbit and to transmissions from
non-geostationary satellites on high-Earth orbit to those on low-Earth orbit. For links
between satellites on the geostationary-satellite orbit, the single entry power
flux-density at all altitudes from 0km to 1000km above the Earth's surface, for all
conditions and for all methods of modulation, shall not exceed -147dBW/m2
/100
MHz for all angles of arrival.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J279"><![CDATA[ In this band, airborne radar of the radiolocation service may be operated
on condition that harmful interference is not caused to the inter-satellite service (see
No. 5.43 of the RR).
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J280"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, radar located on space stations may be operated
on a primary basis in the Earth exploration-satellite service and in the space research
service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J281"><![CDATA[ The 81-81.5GHz band is also allocated to the amateur and
amateur-satellite services on a secondary basis.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J282"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, stations of the fixed, the mobile and the
broadcasting services shall not cause harmful interference to the
broadcasting-satellite stations operating in accordance with the decisions of the 
appropriate frequency assignment planning conference for the broadcasting-satellite
service.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J283"><![CDATA[ Use of this frequency band, by the fixed-satellite service
(Earth-to-space) is limited to feeder links in the broadcasting-satellite service using
the geostationary-satellite orbit.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J284"><![CDATA[ The use of this band by the Earth exploration-satellite (active) and the
space research (active) services is limited to spaceborne cloud radar.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J285"><![CDATA[ Space agencies operating the transmitters and the radio astronomy
stations concerned should mutually plan their operations so as to avoid interference
to some radio astronomy receivers caused by transmissions from space stations of
the Earth exploration-satellite service (active) that are directed into the main beam of
a radio astronomy antenna in the frequency bands 94-94.1GHz and 130-134GHz to
the maximum extent possible.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J286"><![CDATA[ In the bands 105-109.5GHz, 111.8-114.25GHz, 155.5-158.5GHz and
217-226GHz, the use of this allocation is limited to space-based radio astronomy
only.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J287"><![CDATA[ Use of this frequency band by the inter-satellite service is limited to
satellites in the geostationary-satellite orbit. The single-entry power flux-density
produced by a station in the inter-satellite service, for all conditions and for all
methods of modulation, at all altitudes from 0km to 1000km above the Earth’s
surface and in the vicinity of all geostationary orbital positions occupied by passive
sensors, shall not exceed -148dB(W/(m2
·MHz)) for all angles of arrival.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J288"><![CDATA[ The allocation to the Earth exploration-satellite service (active) is
limited to the band 133.5-134GHz.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J289"><![CDATA[ In this frequency band, the allocation to the Earth exploration-satellite
(passive) and space research (passive) services shall terminate on 1 January 2018.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J290"><![CDATA[ Use of this frequency band by the fixed and mobile services shall begin
on 1 January 2018.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J291"><![CDATA[ Use of the bands 174.8-182 GHz and 185-190 GHz by the inter-satellite
service is limited to satellites in the geostationary-satellite orbit. The single-entry
power flux-density produced by a station in the inter-satellite service, for all
conditions and for all methods of modulation, at all altitudes from 0 to 1000km
above the Earth’s surface and in the vicinity of all geostationary orbital positions
occupied by passive sensors, shall not exceed -144dB(W/(m2
·MHz)) for all angles of
arrival.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J292"><![CDATA[ In the bands 200-209GHz, 235-238GHz, 250-252GHz and 265-275GHz,
ground-based passive atmospheric sensing is carried out to monitor atmospheric
constituents.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J293"><![CDATA[ The band 237.9-238GHz is also allocated to the Earth
exploration-satellite service (active) and the space research service (active) for
spaceborne cloud radars only.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J294"><![CDATA[ The use of the range 275-1000GHz by the passive services does not
preclude use of this range by active services.
   ]]></footnote>
   <footnote id="J295"><![CDATA[ The frequency band 1000-3000GHz may be used by both active and
passive services.
   ]]></footnote>
</footnotes>